Michael C Cano

25 Ipil Street Sitio Seville North Fairview QC Philippines

Skype: teampo2

Tel: +1 717 685 9968

Objective:

To seek challenging assignment and responsibility, with an opportunity for growth and career advancement and to make a mark on the work assigned, by true dedication and hard work.

I've been working with OutSystems since 2012, I worked for many insurance companies, banks, consultancy companies. So, it means that I have experience with critical projects.

My backgroud is .NET, I combined .NET and OutSystems, so that's my main knowledge. Since 2014 I've been acting as a technical team leader, managing people and teach them about OutSystems and .NET.

My skill set is as follows:
- PHP 7.x
- Laravel Framework (5.x)
- Mysql/Postgres
- VueJS
- Vuex
- Quasar
- React / Redux
- AngularJS (1.x, 4+)
- RXJS
- socket.io + Pusher + PubNub
- Linux/Apache/Nginx/Varnish Cache
- Stripe Billing/Subscriptions
- Pusher
- Composer
- BDD/TDD Unit Testing / Protractor / Selenium
- Jenkins / Bamboo CI
- GIT
- Wordpress
- Docker/Vagrant
- Redis
- AWS / s3 / Route 53 / ECS / EC2
- GruntJS/Gulp

- Node/NPM/Yarn

- AWS Serverless
I have over 13 years worth of commercial software development experience and my primary languages are PHP and javascript I have also had some significant time in the .NET environment, and C/C++.
I have developed frameworks which suit people who want to develop cloud based SaaS.
API Development:
Twilio
Tesseract
PyTesseract
Backtrader
OpenCV
Pyfolio
OpenGL
Tensorflow
Stripe
BrainTree
Qualifications:
PHP, Rails(2.x - 4.x), PostgreSQL, JavaScript, JQuery, CoffeeScript, AngularJS, ReactJS, Bootstrap 3, Capistrano, Heroku, RSpec, Capybara, Cucumber, ActiveAdmin, Nginx, Passenger, Memcached, Redis, Debian, Ubuntu, PayPal API

.

Experiences:

Total of 4 years experiences

Javascript – 4 years

PHP – 4 years

NodeJS – 3 years

Angular JS – 2 years

Python – 4 years

REACT – 3 years

AWS Lambda – 3 years

Firebase – 4 years

Total of 4 years mobile app development

experience - Xamarin – 4 years

Native mobile app development with

- Objective-C (for iOS) 4 years
- Java (for Android) 4 years

Work History:

ChainBytes – USA company

December 2017 – October 2018

System & Server admin

• deployed and maintained kiosks software of cryptocurrency ATMs all over the world

Setting up Blockchain explorer for several clients, including Fenix Coin and Moore chain. This requires Node. Js server and Node. Js app to establish connection with wallet / full node and								

gather all information in Mongo so client can query through webUI - results are here:

PandaSoft - Philippines Company

Jan 2016 – Feb 2017

- Planned, designed, and built a variety of features for web based applications
- Worked collaboratively using git/github repository management and workflow
- Built uploaders and exporters, business reports, and PDF/CSV generators
- Created modular and maintainable Service Objects for API integration

ImagineWeb Solutions – Philippines company

August 2015 – Jan 2016

- Working mainly with Node.Js and all sort of frameworks, creating dashboards with javascript and with help of server side events, mongodb, redis etc.. also doing ruby programming and a lot of infographic designs.
- Worked on several web sites and systems using jQuery, CSS, AJAX, Flash / Flash Media Server / Wowza Media Server

Projects:

Magento Work

http://trmminc.com/

https://hublenses.com

https://handmade.works/

http://marketplace.skynix.solutions/

http://www.aftereden.nl/